滥药的问题就像一场瘟疫
Drug abuse is a plague.
不断在我国扩散 荼毒生灵
It spreads across our nation, harming our citizens.
毒品 金三角的代名词
Drugs are synonymous with the Golden Triangle.
这个位于泰国、缅甸、老挝的三不管地带
Situated at the borders of Thailand, Myanmar and Laos,
一直是罪犯和毒犯的天堂
this "No Man's Land" has long been safe heaven for criminals and drug dealers.
随着新兴毒品的冒起 降低了制毒门槛
The emergence of new drugs has lowered the threshold of production
更加巩固金三角毒品王国的地位
and solidified the reputation of the Golden Triangle as a drug empire.
湄公河 全长4180公里
At 4,180 km, the Mekong River
是我国和东南亚经贸的重要纽带
is an important link between our nation and Southeast Asia.
也是金三角毒品流入我国的黄金航道
It's also the ideal route for drugs to enter our nation from the Golden Triangle.
称为南方的“鬼门关”
It is known as the "Hell's Gate of the South."
爸 这就是鬼门关
Dad, this is the "Hell's Gate"?
为什么这里叫鬼门关
Why is it called "Hell's Gate"?
这边经常出现土匪
Pirates have plagued this strip of the river for years.
希望这趟不要出什么事
Let's hope luck is on our side this time.
赶紧掉头 通知黄平
Turn around! Notify Huangping!
呼叫黄平号呼叫黄平号
Huangping, Huangping, do you read me?
注意 车内还有两个人质
Listen up, there are two hostages in the vehicle.
闪雷 黑猫 锁定挟持人质的匪徒
Thunder, Black Cat, lock on the hijackers.
闪雷报告 锁定蓝衣目标
This is Thunder, I've locked on to the target in blue.
黑猫报告 锁定灰衣目标
This is Black Cat, I've locked on to the target in gray.
二中队和三中队 马上发起攻坚
Teams two and three, prepare for attack!
接下来是战术射击环节
Our next demonstration is tactical shooting.
第一个科目是双枪合击
First, the eastern regional team
由华东区代表队展示
will demonstrate the dual shot.
在这个科目 两名狙击手同时瞄准目标…
Here, two snipers will aim for the same mark at the same time...
部长 突发事件 湄公河出事了
Minister, we have a situation on the Mekong River.
这宗特大的跨国贩毒案件是我们新上任的
Thanks to our newly appointed
第七军区副司令比塔将军破获
7th Army Region Deputy Commander General Bita,
我们现在请比塔将军
this large-scale multi-national drug trade
给大家解说案件的经过
was taken down in time.
我军收到情报
Upon receiving reliable information,
在湄公河上堵截两艘中国商船
we intercepted two Chinese cargo ships on the Mekong River.
期间我们与十多名中国船员交火
In the process, we exchanged fire with over ten Chinese fishermen.
虽然不幸被他们逃脱
The fishermen fled the scene,
但我军成功在船上搜出九十万颗冰毒
but we were able to uncover 900,000 meth pills on board.
部长
Minister,
我们现在已经和泰方开始交涉
we are in contact with the Thai police,
就是这案件所有的物证
but the Thai military
都掌握在泰国军方手上
is holding all the evidence.
警方无权干预
The Thai police can't interfere.
要等到泰国军方调查结束之后
They can't even begin their investigation
警方才可以接手
until the military completes theirs.
在时间上就不知道要等到什么时候
We don't know how long we'll have to wait.
你找了谁来负责调查组
Who do you have in mind for the task force?
我想找高刚
I'm thinking Gao Gang.
是云南省厅禁毒总队的高刚吗
The captain of the Yunnan Narcotics Team?
是
That's right.
那可是头出了名的倔驴
I hear he's a stubborn one.
部长
Minister,
破这个案子 就要他那股子倔劲
we need his stubbornness to break this case.
你已经找了他
So you've already been in touch with him?
是
Yes.
郝部长…
Minister Hao,
已经答应了
has given his approval.
刚才我跟他说 我说我已经找了你
When I told him that you'd lead the investigation,
他两个眼睛定定的看着我
he glared hard at me.
我的心里真怕他不答应
I really thought that he would turn me down.
烟 赏烟
Pass me a cigarette.
忍忍吧
Come on.
医生都给你下最后通碟了 吃糖
Your doctor ordered you to quit. Take this.
戒烟 滋味不好受
Quitting is tough.
高刚
Gao,
就一条
I only have one condition.
这次要懂规矩
Play this by the book.
放心 当然的了
You got it!
还有一条
One more thing.
以后别再当着我的面抽烟
Don't ever smoke in front of me.
死人呀
Dead body!
真没天理 太残忍了
This is just too cruel!
看他们的样子分明就是谋杀
It's clearly murder!
又绑手又蒙眼的
They've been blindfolded with their hands tied!
大家好
Hello, viewers.
我们现在回到码头现场
We return to the pier now
带大家来看最新情况
for the latest developments.
泰军已经确认这十三具尸体
The Thai military confirms that the 13 victims
就是陆兴八号…
were indeed crew members...
是
Yes?
对不起“老板”
I'm sorry, Boss.
是我做得不够周到
I didn't do a good job.
我会把事情好好办妥的
I'll take care of it.
泰方报称 军方曾与船民发生枪战
The Thai reports say that the military exchanged fire with the fishermen.
根据当天湄公河的流速
But judging by Mekong River's flow of stream that day,
假如双方真的遭遇了枪战
if there really was a shootout,
而两艘商船都是毒贩的话
and if the two cargo ships really were smuggling drugs,
那他们应该是一边开枪射击
they should've been firing
一边加速逃跑才对
and speeding away at the same time.
但是在案发现场
But at the crime scene,
我们根据弹孔的分布 弹道定位的集中
the bullet hole distribution and trajectories clustered around the same spot.
可以确定 所有弹孔都是定位射击形成
We can confirm that the bullets were fired in a stationary position.
这个结论推翻了之前泰方公布的结果
This conclusion overturns the Thai reports.
更为明显的是
There's something even more evident.
我们在其中一个船舱的铁板上
We've found a number of possible bullet scratches
找到多个疑似弹痕的痕迹
on a metal panel on one of the ships.
从弹痕的集中和角度来推断
Judging by their degree and concentration,
射击的方向不可能是从岸上射过来
the shots could not have come from the shore.
而是在船舱里射击的
They were fired on the ship instead.
另外根据死亡船员尸体上的弹孔角度来分析
Combine that with the bullet angle analysis on the victims,
可以肯定是遭到行刑式的四十五度射击
we can confirm it was a 45-degree point blank execution.
情报网方面有进展吗
Any updates from your intel networks?
我们在金三角情报员奇夫
Our Golden Triangle intelligence officer Qifu
刚刚得到一个消息
just got a lead.
在案发前的两周
Two weeks before the shooting,
有一个毒品交易被黑吃黑了
a drug deal was ambushed.
这批毒品的数量正好是九十万颗
The amount of meth pills stolen also happened to be 900,000.
有没有找到相关的人
Did we find anyone involved in the theft?
有
We did.
奇夫其中一个线人已经在跟踪他
One of Qifu's informants is tracking him.
停
Stop!
走开
Move!
进去
Get in!
有枪
They're armed!
不许动
Don't move!
这是我最后一次问你
I'm asking you one last time.
是谁叫你偷那九十万颗冰毒
Who hired you to steal those 900,000 meth pills?
你干什么妈的你干什么
What the fuck are you doing?
准备受死吧
You're about to die.
是岩多帕
It's Yan Taung Pha!
收买我的是岩多帕
Yan Taung Pha hired me!
是他们把那批冰毒放到那两艘船上的
He told me to put the meth pills on the two ships!
是糯卡集团的岩多帕
Yan Taung Pha from Naw Khan's group?
我真的只知道这么多…
That's all I know, I swear...
救我 救我…
Save me, Save me...
这个毒头糯卡到底是什么背景
Who the hell is this drug lord Naw Khar?
糯卡的身份比较复杂
Naw Khar has a rather complicated history.
他的祖藉是缅甸
He's originally from Myanmar,
但是他在泰国和老挝都有身份
but he's also a citizen of Thailand and Laos.
八十年代金三角的毒王坤沙就是他的头儿
In the 80s, he worked for Khun Sa, the drug kingpin of the Golden Triangle.
坤沙向缅甸军政府投降以后
When Khun Sa surrendered to the Burmese government,
糯卡收编了他大部份的人员
Naw Khar absorbed most of Khun Sa's men
然后勾结当地的民兵 重新建立武装势力
and built a new force with them and the local militia.
糯卡和坤沙的行事作风完全不一样
Khun Sa and Naw Khar have completely different styles.
糯卡本人吸毒 行事狂妄自大
Naw Khar is a reckless and arrogant drug addict.
他的手下大部份都有吸毒的习惯
Most of his men use drugs as well.
糯卡欺压弱小的部落
He oppresses the small tribes.
又会抓走小孩子当娃娃兵
He turns the kids into child soldiers
更用毒品来控制他们
and controls them with drugs.
当地各部族也被迫加入他们的集团
Many local tribes are forced to work with his group.
我们一直想跟老缅泰三国
We've always wanted to work with Laos, Burma and Thailand
共同改善湄公河的治安情况
to improve security along the Mekong River,
但是一直都没有能够达成共识
but an agreement was never reached.
这次的血雨腥风 手段如此残忍
This case involves so much bloodshed and brutality.
这正好是个机会
This is the perfect time
我们再度要求三国联合巡逻
for us to call for joint patrols again.
还十三位中国船员一个清白
We have to clear our fishermen's names.
给全国老百姓一个交待
We owe the nation an explanation!
这次召开四国会议
The purpose of this joint meeting
是要打破地域上的限制
is to break past geographical boundaries.
让三国允许我国人员入境参与调查
Let Chinese officers investigate in the three nations
协助捉拿四国共同的罪犯
for the capture of our common target.
诸位
Gentlemen,
我方已经掌握了一名泰国的污点证人瓦拉
we have secured a witness from Thailand named Wala.
他已经向我方证实
He has already confessed that
整件栽赃陷害事件
this frameup was orchestrated
是受金三角的毒枭糯卡指使
by Golden Triangle drug lord Naw Khar.
若要查出真相 必须先逮捕糯卡
To get to the truth, we must apprehend Naw Khar.
敬礼
Salute!
我们要给金三角的犯罪势力
We must send a strong message
一个强烈的信息
to the criminals in the Golden Triangle.
当国民安全受到威胁的时候
When our citizens are under threat,
国家不会坐视不理
We will not stand idly by.
我们会以武制武 出动最精锐的缉毒人员
We fight aggression with aggression. Our elite narcotics officers
全力维护湄公河流域的安全通航
will make Mekong River a safe passage for everyone!
四国在此联合宣布
The four nations jointly announce
联合专案组正式成立
the establishment of the joint operation task force.
四国将尽快查清一零五案的案情
Together, we will solve the "October 5" case with great urgency.
缉拿并严惩杀害中国十三名船员的凶手
We will capture the culprit who murdered 13 Chinese fishermen!
我们这次联合行动的第一击
This is our first joint operation.
目标是要打击糯卡的犯罪集团
Our goal is to subdue Naw Khar's group.
根据可靠的线报
With the help of reliable sources,
我们三国都已经掌握到
we managed to locate Naw Khar's various
糯卡不同的制毒和贩毒地点
drug factories and trafficking spots.
为防风声走漏 我们会在同一时间行动
We must hit them on the blind side, and we have to make our move at once!
四国联合行动指挥官授权我方人员
The joint task force commander has given us authorization
在特殊情况下可以使用武器
to use force under special circumstances.
一旦遇到紧急情况
If there's an urgent situation,
必须全力支援
we must provide full support!
明白
Understood!
现在中国已经施压 要三国行动
China is making the other three nations take action.
你们暂时停止所有活动吧
You should all lay low until the dust settles.
这里是我们的地方
This is our turf!
泰、缅、老从来都管不了
Laos, Burma and Thailand never got us,
为什么现在要怕他妈的中国
so why the fuck should we fear China?
“老板”已经很不满
Boss is furious.
他要你交待
He demands you to explain
这件事为何会发展到这个地步
how things got this far.
他要的 我都做了
I've done everything he's asked for.
至于我怎样做 他不用理会
How I did it is none of his business.
如果真要我交待…
If he really wants an explanation...
你就拿他去交待吧 宋哥
There's your explanation, P'Som!
我糯卡什么都不怕
I'm Naw Khar, I'm not afraid of anything!
高刚
Gao,
由于糯卡在三国犯案累累
Naw Khar is wanted for many crimes in the other three nations.
为了避免他落入其他国家受审
We can't let him fall into the hands of the other nations,
我们必须抢先捉到糯卡
so we have to be the first to get him.
奇夫已经掌握了糯卡集团的资料
Qifu has already obtained intel on Naw Khar's group.
高刚
Gao Gang.
方新武
Fang Xinwu.
收了你这么多年情报
We finally meet in person
这回终于见到真人了
after getting your intel for so many years.
彼此彼此
Nice to finally meet you too.
这片茶山面积可不小
Quite a huge farm you've got here.
你现在看到这十几个山头
The hills that you see in front of you
以前都是罂粟田
were all opium farms.
看来替代种植效果显著
Looks like alternative development changed everything.
不错
That's good.
但是
The problem is...
却改变不了金三角的本质
it hasn't changed the nature of the Golden Triangle.
他们都是来自附近小部落的原居民
These are residents of villages nearby.
毒枭逼他们种罂粟
Drug dealers forced them to plant opium.
不听话 就被剁手剁脚
When they refused, their limbs were chopped off.
早安
Morning!
奇先生 早上好
Good morning, Mr. Qifu.
不要忘记今晚的电影晚会
Don't forget our movie screening tonight.
七点没问题 谢谢奇先生
7 o'clock. See you there, Mr. Qifu.
情报显示
Our intel tell us that
糯卡和他主要团伙
Naw Khar and his backbone members
已经彻离了所有原本据点
have left their strongholds.
翁煞 行动组长
Ongsa, operations commander.
贴身保卫 勒索打劫
A bodyguard who also handles kidnapping and looting.
依达 生意交易
Ya Ta, business and trading.
桑吉 货运、洗黑钱
San Kyi, logistics and money laundering.
你现在看到的这三个人是集团的骨干成员
These three men are the backbone members of Naw Khar's group.
由糯卡独立安排分工
Naw Khar arranges their duties himself.
拿突是谁
Who is Nah Htuu?
糯卡的大儿子
Naw Khar's eldest son.
糯卡这张照片怎么这么模糊
Why is Naw Khar's picture so blurry?
那张照片是十年前国际刑警拍的
That photo was taken ten years ago by the Interpol.
也是唯一的一张
It also happens to be the one and only.
不应该
How could that be?
十年来他一直在活动
He's been active for the past decade.
怎么可能没有更新的资料
Why isn't there more on him?
糯卡这家伙做事非常隐密
Naw Khar always acts under the radar.
目前他潜伏在金三角发展特区的山脉里
He's hiding out in the mountains of the Golden Triangle Special Region.
特区的位置就在泰、老、缅三国的交接处
It sits at the intersecting point of Thailand, Laos and Myanmar.
由三国共同管治
It's under the three countries' jurisdiction,
但是由于地理原因 执法困难
but its location makes law enforcement almost impossible.
加上贪污腐败严重
Adding corruption into the equation,
最后就成为三不管地带 犯罪的天堂
the region is a "No Man's Land", a paradise for criminals.
糯卡的手下岩多帕现在就被朴扎关在这里
This is where Puja is holding Naw Khar's man Yan Taung Pha.
如果把他救出来
If we can extract Yan Taung Pha,
我们就可以拿到一些线索
it should get us some leads.
这个朴扎是什么人
Who is this Puja?
特区五大毒贩
One of the five kingpins in the Special Region,
除了糯卡 实力最强的是朴扎
He's the most powerful one after Naw Khar.
你有什么想法
What's your plan?
我已经安排好线人
I've already planted a mole.
但是要记住
But remember,
不管成不成功
whatever happens,
行动时问只有十五分钟
you have only 15 minutes to complete the mission.
这个案子很复杂
This is a complicated case.
幕后的势力也很大
There's a larger power working behind the scenes.
所以我们要小心 不要被当地警方发现
We must be careful and stay out of the local police's sights.
万一出了事 记住
If anything happens,
身份绝对不能透露
keep your identities secret.
整个城区就只有一个出入口
There's only one entry way for the entire district.
在这有一个金属探测器
A metal detector has been installed there.
所有进去的人都不能带枪
That means no one can carry guns inside.
以免不必要的麻烦
It's how they keep trouble away.
虽然城里枪险不大
The chance of a gunfight is minimal,
但是那班忘命徒刀斧更加凶残
but these guys are brutal with their axes.
每天中午十二点
Every day at noon,
会有一台车到贼区送啤酒
a beer truck arrives for delivery.
等候时间是十五分钟
The whole process takes about 15 minutes.
计划是要利用啤酒货车把岩多帕运走
The plan is to use the beer truck to extract Yan Tuang Pha.
二郎 你负责用无人机监控整个地区
Panoptes, monitor the surroundings with your drone.
如果事情有变
If anything happens,
我会通知你开干扰器
I'll ask you to activate the signal jammer.
冰冰 你带哮天负责接应
Aphrodite, take Bingo with you.
其余的会与野牛突击队做支援
The others will follow the Bulls as backup.
所有配枪都会用低速橡胶子弹
All guns will be loaded with low-speed rubber bullets.
我们的目标
Our mission
就是要在不杀任何人的情况下
is to extract Yan Taung Pha
把岩多帕救出来
without causing any casualty.
局长 所有人就位
Everyone is in position, Chief.
高队 车到
Captain, the truck is here.
情况有变 没有发现目标
We have a situation, target is missing.
巩猜
Gongchai,
目标不在原来位置 有没有其他地方
the target is missing. Where else he can be?
之前还在…
He was right there earlier...
线人说没见过人带走岩多帕
The informant didn't see anyone move Yan Taung Pha.
小冰 放哮天进来
Aphrodite, let Bingo in.
收到
Copy!
顺利进入
Bingo is in.
大师
Poseidon,
按计划进行
let's stick to the plan.
收到
Copy that.
哮天
Bingo.
哮天 嗅嗅
Bingo, sniff.
踪
Go!
记住 我们的目标是朴扎
Remember, our target is Puja.
那岩多帕呢
What about Yan Taung Pha?
他妈的杀了他
Just fucking kill him.
他让卡头丢脸了
He's embarrassed our boss.
注意 目标有生命危险
Listen up. The target's life is in danger.
我准备硬抢
I'm gonna snatch him!
二郎 截断他们的信号
Panoptes, jam their signal now!
收到
Copy!
听到吗 听到吗
Can you hear me? Do you copy?
走
Go!
去支援高队 走
Let's go back Captain up!
我们暴露了
We're exposed.
二郎 有没有其他退路
Panotpes, any other way out?
从天台走 上面会有一条钢缆
Take the rooftop. There's a cable there,
连到另一个天台
it's connected to another rooftop.
哮天
Bingo,
撤
retreat!
里面有事情发生了
There's trouble in there!
快封锁大门
Lock the gate!
驶过来
Get over here!
走快走
Go! Go!
小冰
Aphrodite,
你去接应 往前走两百米左转
pick up Captain. Turn left in 200m!
收到
Copy!
你们留在这里
You guys stay right here.
去支援高队
Go help Captain!
好
Okay!
看看那副网能不能用
See if we can use that net!
高队 先走
Captain, you go ahead!
来不及 走
We're out of time! Go!
高队 越过天台十二点方向尽处有矮房
Captain, there's a hut at your 12 o'clock.
可以跳下小巷 小巷尾左拐有出口
Jump down to the alleyway. Turn left at the end for the exit.
直走三百米 过了蓝色铁闸左拐
At 300 meters, take a left after the blue metal gates.
两点方向有一条小路
Then take the small path at the 2 o'clock direction.
快呀
Hurry up!
野牛队 我们马上冲出来 请求支援
Bulls, we're on our way out. Request for assistance!
郁局 情况紧急
Chief, we have an urgent situation.
野牛队请求行动
Permission for the Bulls to strike!
上
Granted.
爆
Blow it!
妈的
Fuck!
高队 快
Captain! Hurry!
快
Hurry!
中国人
Chinese?
快快开车
Move it!
你们是什么人
(Burmese) Who are you people?
为什么要救我
Why did you save me?
弹匣
Ammo!
快译通
Hermes!
我们的车后面有追击
We have enemies in pursuit!
高队 我在后面 很快到
We're right behind you, Captain!
小冰 你没事吧
Aphrodite, are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine!
操
Fuck!
操蛋
Fucking hell!
这里是金三角啊高队
This is the Golden Triangle, Captain!
金三角又怎么了
So what if this is the Golden Triangle?!
我的线人现在曝光了
My informant is exposed!
不是说好了吗
Didn't we have an agreement?
十五分钟 你们就只有十五分钟
15 minutes means 15 minutes!
不管任务有没有完成
You were to fucking retreat,
你都得他妈给我出来
no matter what!
你来这里就得配合我
Out here, you have to do things my way!
你有完没完
Are you finished?
救岩多帕就只有这一次机会
We had one chance to save Yan Taung Pha.
我必须这么做
I had to take it!
救不了这一次 我们再找别的线索
If we had failed, we could've found other leads!
你是他妈提供情报的
You're fucking responsible for intel.
具体实施的是他妈我
I make the fucking calls!
如果你跟我还要继续合作下去
If we're going to keep working together,
你就要按照我的方法
you have to follow my lead!
别费劲了 坐我的车吧
Forget it. Take my car.
前面路口左转
Make a left at the corner ahead.
哪个路口
Which one?
过头了
You just passed it.
怎么不早说
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
怎么了
What's wrong?
扑扎找上门了 我要马上离开
Puja is hot on my trail. I need to leave now.
别紧张…
Don't panic...
火车站等 我马上带钱过来 好吗
Get to the train station. I'll bring some cash. Okay?
巩猜被发现了
Gongchai's on the run.
你在车上等我
Wait for me in the car.
有什么事赶紧通知我
Call me if anything happens.
有事打给我
Call me if you need anything.
怎么了
What's the matter?
对不起 奇夫…
I'm sorry, Qifu...
我不想这样的
I didn't want it to be like this!
他们抓到我了…
They got to me first...
你要救救我
you have to help me!
他们去哪了
Where did they go?
你在什么位置 我过去找你
What's your location? I'm coming over.
你别过来 我曝光了
Don't! I'm exposed.
我现在在月台最远的商店
I'm behind the snack shop at the far end of the platform.
巩猜会在我冲出来的位置
Gongchai will be where I dash out.
你过来保护他
Help me protect him.
其他我会搞定
I'll handle the rest.
给我仔细找
Search again!
那边
Over there!
让开
Piss off!
放开我
Let me go!
今天这一款
I have to say...
看着有点别扭
I'm not used to seeing that look.
你还是扮上吧
You should keep your disguise on!
我看你现在这样 倒是挺顺眼
Well, you don't look too bad yourself.
哪吒 把盘递给我
Icarus, pass me a plate.
好的
Sure.
小心点 别烫着
Watch out, don't burn yourself.
我觉得…
I think...
你是不是长得像那个谁
You really remind me of somebody.
看出来了
Yep!
像谁像谁
Who is that?
好多人都说我像
Many people said so!
像…
But I can't tell who...
看好了
Watch!
郭富城
Aaron Kwok!
郭富城…
Aaron Kwok...
郭富城
Aaron Kwok.
我对你的情报开始有点怀疑了 真的
I'm starting to doubt your intel.
开饭了
Time to eat!
互相介绍一下
Let's introduce ourselves!
我叫郭旭
My name is Guo Xu!
你叫他大师就行 整天唠唠叨叨的
Just call him Poseidon. He's always moody.
我是他妹妹 郭冰
I'm his sister, Guo Bing!
千万别叫她冰冰 一叫她冰冰她就咬人
Never call her by her code name. She'll be really pissed.
都倒满
Fill it up!
为什么
Why?
因为她怕别人笑话…
People make fun of her all the time.
不许说
Don't say it!
因为…因为…
The reason is...
因为她也叫冰冰 人家也叫冰冰
Her code name is Aphrodite,
怎么冰味不一样
but she looks nothing like a Greek Goddess!
今天不让你喝酒了
No more beer for you tonight.
你好
How do you do?
很高兴认识你 我负责翻译
Glad to meet you. I'm the translator.
我是快译通
Call me Hermes!
该你了
You're up.
我…我叫江星…
I'm Jiang Xing...
负责爆…爆破…
I specialize in ex... ex... explosives.
所以他不怎么爱说话
That's why he doesn't like to talk.
跟条木头一样 我们给他起个外号叫木星
He's sharp like a spear. That's why we gave him the name Ares.
但是执行起任务来 那可是句句铿锵
When he's in action, his commands are always dead-on.
哥 吃饭都堵不住你的嘴
Not even food can shut your mouth, brother.
谢文峰 大家都叫我哪吒
Xie Wenfeng. They call me Icarus.
他总是跟他老爸作对
He's always acting against his father's wishes.
傅保卫
Fu Baowei.
叫我二郎
Call me Panoptes!
通天眼
One hundred eyes?
我负责无人机
I specialize in drones!
它叫哮天
He's Bingo.
你们这个队满天神佛
A team of Greek deities.
厉害 厉害
I'm impressed.
他应该也有外号
What about his code name?
好啦来来来
Come on. Let's do a toast!
四大黑之一…
The one and only...
包公
Zeus.
碰一个
Cheers!
好
Come on!
来 干
Bottoms up!
我们调查组在调查岩多帕的时候
During our background check on Yan Taung Pha,
又发现新的线索
we picked up a new lead.
我们发现岩多帕经常通过一个中间人
We found out that he has been producing meth
大量购买一种制造冰毒的原材料
with raw ingredients bought via a middleman.
是麻黄素
Ephedra?
是中药 麻黄草
It's medicinal ephedra.
找到那个供货商了吗
Do we have the supplier?
这个人叫张大安
His name is Zhang Da-An.
是内地的一个中草药商
He's a Chinese medicine merchant from China.
不过这个人现在在四川已经被我们控制了
We already have him under our custody in Sichuan.
交待了接头的中间人是谁吗
Did he say who the middleman is?
在金三角 糯卡只有两个代理人
Naw Khar only has two middlemen in Golden Triangle.
一个不知道姓名 另一个就是这个沙先生
We don't know who the first person is, but the other is Mr. Zar.
现在我们掌握唯一的线索就是
At the moment, our only lead
找到一个替沙先生出面的人 叫皮尔
is the guy who takes care of Mr. Zar's business, named Pierre.
我有一个想法
I have an idea.
看来我们得演出戏
We're going to put on a show.
我给你安排一个角色
I'll come up with a role for you.
行
Sure,
只要你不要我演人妖就行
as long as I don't play a ladyboy.
演了也不像
He doesn't look the part anyway.
喂
Yeah?
皮尔 我是大安
Hello Pierre, this is Da-An.
听着 我这边遇到了一点麻烦
Listen, I just ran into some kind of trouble.
这里的警察把我查得很紧
The police here are keeping a close eye on me.
那我的货怎么办
What about my stuff?
你放心吧
Don't worry about it.
我安排了我的新搭档来送货
I have already arranged a new partner to deliver your stuff.
新拍档
A new partner?
这是我们之间的生意 这人信得过吗
This is supposed to be our business. How am I gonna trust him?
当然
Why not?
能和我合作的人当然可信 就像你一样
I trust my partner just like I trust you.
你会喜欢他的 记得好好招待他
Treat him really well. You're gonna like him.
好吧 别出岔子
Alright. Just don't screw up.
大安应该早点介绍我们认识
Da-An should've introduced us earlier!
我们一定很合拍
We're gonna get on well.
那你想干什么在中国卖垃圾
What do you want to do? Sell crap to China?
反正都能赚钱
We'll be rich!
你想在中国卖垃圾
You want to sell crap to China!
这不就是我正在干的事吗
That's what I am doing already!
难道我不是吗
I'm already selling them, man.
我来 我来请
Give me the bill!
不用 我来 给我 我来请
No! Come on, bring it over! I got it!
你想请
You wanna pay the bills?
那就让你请吧
You be the boss.
反正我讨厌请客
I hate paying bills anyway!
现在你该叫我做老大吧
Now I be the boss?
你知道吗
You know what we got?
我真的感觉和你…
We got that thing...
“相疯很晚”
Too bad we didn't meet earlier.
是“相逢恨晚”
It's "Xiang Feng Hen Wan."
随便吧
Whatever.
你那里也不用去
You're not going anywhere.
跟着我去泡几个女的 爽一番
You stay with me, we'll get you some girls, we'll clean you up,
今晚我们一定要尽兴
we're gonna have some fun tonight, boy.
说话可他妈要算数啊…
Don't fucking lie to me...
嘿
Hey!
哇操 哇操…
What the fuck! What the fuck...
怎么在这儿也能碰到你
Fancy running into you here!
死去哪了 郭昆
Long time no see, Guo Kun!
太巧了
What a coincidence!
混得不错
You're doing pretty well, eh?
你来这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我不就是跟钱老大
I was in Myanmar with Mr. Qian
到缅甸这边来谈谈开赌场的事
about setting up a casino over there,
顺道出来走走
so I thought I'd stop by!
钱老大也在这儿
Mr. Qian is here too?
在 在上面
Yeah, he's upstairs.
三带二
Full house!
什么他妈牌…
What the hell...
钱老大
Mr. Qian!
小奇 等会儿 马上完
Hold on, Xiaoqi. I'll be with you in a minute.
没有吧有没有
Pass? You pass?
出牌
Put it out!
不出
No way!
没有吧
Pass?
没有
No!
炸
Bomb!
钱老大太牛逼了…
Mr. Qian is really something...
小奇
Xiaoqi!
钱老大
Mr. Qian!
怎么他妈在这儿碰上你了
How the fuck did you end up in here?
我当然是嗅到钱老大你的钱味了
I followed the smell of your money, of course!
哥们最喜欢那种嗅着钱味的狗
I love puppies that are good at sniffing money.
小奇 赶上了
Come, Xiaoqi,
拿着
take this.
拿着 谢谢钱老板
Just take it! Thanks Mr.Qian.
全他妈是我今天赢的
I won all this today.
赢这这富二代 拿着拿着
I won it all from this rich brat. Just take it!
谢谢钱老大
Thanks, Mr. Qian!
高兴吧
Happy?
高兴死了 谢谢钱老大
Fucking ecstatic! Thanks!
转个圈
Take a spin.
摇摇尾巴给我看看
Wag your tail for me.
摇摇尾巴
Come on!
没问题钱老大
Of course, Mr. Qian.
这兄弟谁呀
Who's this fella?
皮尔 过来
Pierre, come over here!
这是我兄弟皮尔
This is my good friend Pierre.
钱老大 钱多多老板
He is Mr. Qian.
钱多多老板 你好
Nice to meet you, Mr. Qian.
跟中国人做生意
If you wanna do business with the Chinese,
怎样也得学两句地道的中文吧
you'll have to learn some Mandarin, won't you?
钱老大是干哪一门的
Mr. Qian, what does he do exactly?
他搞赌 你有所不知了
Gambling, man! What do you think?
在全中国他拥有两百多个地下赌场
This guy owns 200 underground casinos in China,
也搞很多钱庄生意
plus God knows how many private banks.
兄弟 我觉得我们三个要一起合作
Brother! You, me, and him, we're gonna work together.
我肯定我们能干些大事
I tell you now. We're gonna work this out.
那当然
You don't say!
听着
Listen,
他之前已在找我干点…
he's already asked me to do some...
你明白吗
You know?
皮尔先生
Mr. Pierre.
小奇跟姓钱的和两个保镖去了公主夜总会
Xiaoqi, Qian and two bodyguards have gone to the Princess Club.
他们之后会上澳门万豪搏彩集团的游艇
Then they'll board a yacht owned by Macau's Wanhao Casino.
我打听过
I hear that
姓钱的在万豪长期包了
Qian is the banker for
四个大注码的贵宾厅做庄
four high roller lounges at Wanhao.
皮尔先生
Mr. Pierre.
他们带着二十多个女伴上了游艇
They've brought over 20 girls to the yacht.
我会派人在岸边继续监视
I'll have people keep a close eye from the shore.
相信我 他们是有实力的
Trust me! These guys are real deal.
皮尔
Pierre,
你知道怎样才能煎出一块好牛排吗
do you know what makes a good steak?
牛排的质量、火候的控制和时间
Good quality of meat, the right temperature, the right cooking time.
我都教了你多少遍
How many times have I taught you
所有事情都不能只看表面
to look beneath the surface?
关键是
It's all about
煮牛排那个人有没有细心去对待他
how carefully the chef treats the steak.
当然 沙先生
Of course, Mr. Zar.
沙先生 您的朋友到了
Mr. Zar, your friend has arrived.
您好 沙先生
Hello, Mr. Zar.
多谢 沙先生
Thank you, Mr. Zar.
谢谢
Thank you.
我离开这里差不多五年
I've been gone for five years,
都没有什么大起色
and I have nothing to show for it.
所以想回来金三角
That's why I've come back to the Golden Triangle.
美国那边不容易混的
America isn't the easiest place to make a living in.
最近皮尔认识了一名中国人
There's this Chinese guy that Pierre came across not long ago.
他想跟我做点交易
And he wanted to talk business.
我在想 既然中国你比较熟
As I'm sure, you're more familiar with China than me.
不如你帮我去了解一下
Why don't you go and check him out for me?
沙先生 跟中国人谈生意我最在行
Doing business with the Chinese is my specialty!
我一定替你开一个好价钱
I'll make sure you get a good deal!
钱老板
Mr. Qian,
你们搞赌的真的遇上黄金时代
this is the golden age for the gambling business.
现在中国大陆人人有钱
Everyone in China is so rich nowadays!
那占蓬先生一年大概能跟我提供多少货
Mr. Jitpong, how much product are you able to supply annually?
两吨
Two tons!
两吨绝对没问题
We can definitely deal with two tons.
你都说了黄金时代
You just said that we're in the golden age!
两吨
Two tons?
两吨货前两年还差不多
Two tons were barely enough a few years ago.
现在翻了几番了
We do much bigger deals now.
我现在要跟你谈的生意
I'm talking about a minimum of
一年至少六吨
six tons per year!
那个叫占蓬的是谁
Hey, who's that Jitpong guy?
我以为只有你处理沙先生的业务
I thought you're the only guy who's dealing with Mr. Zar's business?
占蓬是从美国来的
Jitpong is from America.
沙先生可欣赏他了
And Mr. Zar likes him a lot.
钱老板 佣金方面我们可以商量
Mr. Qian, we can always talk about commission later.
我跟你说
I'm telling you,
中间人不只你一家
you're not the only middleman in this business.
主动要找我谈的人多呢
There are plenty of people I can talk to.
我是看在你跟小奇的关系才跟你谈
I'm only talking to you because Xiaoqi can vouch for you,
但是今天我对你很失望
but you've really disappointed me today.
我他妈是有钱
Yes I am rich,
可我也不是一傻子
but I'm not a fucking imbecile!
知道吗
Got it?
钱老板
Mr. Qian!
钱老板 我们可以商量
Mr. Qian, we can always negotiate.
钱老板
Mr. Qian,
价钱我们可以再谈
we can negotiate for the right price.
可以再谈
We can always talk again.
我现在跟你们谈的是每年十五亿的生意
We're talking about a 1.5 billion-per-year business here!
总之市场控制在我手里
Look, the market is in my hands.
如果你想往下谈
If you want to keep talking,
把货主约出来 我们一块儿谈
get your supplier and we'll talk together.
我后天离开这 给你两天的时间
I'm leaving in two days. I want an answer by then!
开心 开心 喝酒 喝酒
Don't get mad. Let's drink.
喝酒我们自己喝去
We can drink on our own.
小奇
Xiaoqi!
没想到这个案子会碰上他
I didn't think that we'd run into him in this case.
我觉得
I think that
这个案子
you should step away
你可能要暂时回避
from this case for now.
你怕我杀了他
You're afraid that I'll kill him.
新武
Xinwu,
当初你选择来这里当情报员
I was worried when you chose to come here
我不是没有担心
to be an intelligence officer.
但是我最终决定还是派你来
But I decided to send you here anyway
是因为我相信你是一名缉毒警
because I trust you to be narcotics officer.
等案子结束了
When this is all over,
我们一起把他押回去
we'll catch him together.
新武跟那个占蓬是什么关系
What exactly went down between him and Jitpong?
现在这个占蓬就是当年的刑登
The Jitpong today used to be called Xing Deng.
刑登在五年前是国内的一个毒贩
He was a drug dealer in China five years ago.
方新武十年的女友就是被他害死的
Fang Xinwu's girlfriend of ten years died because of him.
之后刑登逃到金三角
Xing Deng fled to the Golden Triangle,
从此失去了他的消息
and we've lost track of him since.
你帮我回去偷你男朋友电脑里面所有资料
Steal all the data from your boyfriend's computer for me.
一次
One time.
就一次
Just this once.
不行…
I can't...
我这样会害到他…
I can't do that to him...
你男友是缉毒的
Your boyfriend is an narcotics officer.
如果全世界知道他女友吸毒的话
If everyone knows that his girlfriend is a junkie,
你猜他会怎样
how do you think he'd react?
赢 赢 赢
Win! Win! Win!
快点快点
Hurry up!
怎样
So what?
最近的形势 你不是不知道吧
You are aware of the current situation, right?
我相信这个钱先生是真材实料
I'm positive that this Mr. Qian is a reliable source.
我这边的占蓬已经查过他了
My guy Jitpong checked him out.
你叫他们先做一次
Do a deal with them,
之后才决定是否见面吧
and then we'll see if he deserves a meeting.
这也是要试试他们
We need to find out
到底是不是真的有实力
whether he's really got deep pockets.
先来五百万美金吧
Let's start with five million US dollars.
出货时间、地点我再通知你
I'll keep you posted on the drop-off time and place.
喂 怎样了
Hey, what's happening?
兄弟 可以交易了
The deal's on, brother.
我再告诉你时间地点
I'll let you know the time and place.
太棒了…
Oh yeah...
好 我立即通知钱先生
Alright, I'll tell Mr. Qian right away.
上钩了
They've taken the bait.
你刚到这儿工作的时候
When you first moved here,
也不太适应吧
did you have a hard time adjusting?
还行
I got by.
自从我知道我女友吸毒的那天起
From the moment I found out my girlfriend was an addict,
我就知道今后我该干什么
I knew what I had to do.
没有什么比直接打击毒贩更让我兴奋
Nothing excites me more than taking down drug dealers every day.
爸爸 你喜不喜欢猫
Daddy, do you like cats?
爸爸的小情人
Daddy's little lover.
幸福美满的家庭
What a lovely family.
我离婚了
I'm divorced.
闺女现在跟她妈妈住
My daughter lives with her mother now.
你现在在这里很想她吧
You must miss her, being all the way out here.
想孩子
Of course I do.
大家注意 糯卡已经上钩
Listen up, Naw Khar has taken our bait.
他们要求先交易
Their request is to do the exchange
确认我们的钱没有问题 才会在商场露面
and verify the money before showing up at the mall.
交易方面由二郎和木星负责
Panoptes and Ares are in charge of the exchange.
完成后 木星在后面支持哪吒的跟踪
After that, Ares will back up Icarus' surveillance mission.
二郎 你立刻赶来商场和我会合
Panoptes will join us at the mall immediately.
你们的任务完成后立即通报
Let us know as soon as the deal is completed.
另外大师、冰冰、快译通
Poseidon, Aphrodite, and Hermes,
你们早一步跟我到商场
you'll come with me to the mall.
商场分别有四个出口
The mall has a total of four exits.
野牛的便衣队会在外面负责待命
The Bulls will be stand by outside
跟踪目标
to track down any target.
记着
Remember,
对方选择见面的地方人流是多
we're meeting in a crowded area.
不知道对方会有多少人混在人群里
We don't know how many of their guys are in the crowd.
所以要多加留意
Be vigilant at all times.
把钱丢到下层天桥
Throw the money to the road below.
我的货在哪
Where's my stuff?
在你右边第五和第六个油桶里
Inside the fifth and sixth barrel to your right.
发现四号目标人物桑吉
Target number four San Kyi spotted!
哪吒 你肯定
Icarus, are you sure?
肯定
Positive.
我上一次见到你
When we met last time,
我就觉得你很眼熟
I thought that you looked familiar.
你在中国混过吗
Have you spent time in China?
是
Hello.
钱没有问题
The money is good.
好
Okay.
三号人物依达出现 东门
Target number three Ya Ta has arrived. East Gate.
来了
They're here.
您好
Hi!
Hello.
让我介绍一下
Allow me to introduce...
依达先生
Mr. Ya Ta.
钱先生
Mr. Qian.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
幸会幸会
Likewise.
请坐
Have a seat!
郁局
Chief.
什么情况
What's going on?
您听
Here.
这里有五百万美金
Here is five million US dollars.
糯卡说
Naw Khar said
其中一百万
one million
是给你当作湄公河那件事的酬金
is for what you did at the Mekong River.
余下的 麻烦洗干净后
As for the rest, please make it clean
转到金三角赌场户口
and deposit it to his account at the Golden Triangle Casino.
不是说好一百五十万吗
I thought the deal was 1.5 million?
糯卡说你做得不够好
Naw Khar felt that Boss was against him
令“老板”对他有意见
because you are not doing a good job.
桑吉
San Kyi,
“老板”已经对糯卡非常不满
Boss has been unhappy with Naw Khar for some time now.
我告诉你 以现在局势
Just so you know, under the current circumstances,
若然“老板”出手 糯卡时代将会逝去
the Naw Khar era could end anytime if Boss so chooses to.
至于你
As for you, my friend,
我一直都看好你
I always thought you have great potential.
我也有对“老板”提及过你
I even mentioned your name to Boss.
一年十五亿的货源他们没有问题
They can definitely supply 1.5 billion worth of goods per year,
但是合作的方式他们有些想法
but they have some ideas about the business terms.
第一
One,
我们必须是钱先生的独家供货人
we'll be Mr. Qian's exclusive supplier.
第二
Two,
我们要入股经营 参与销售
we will be your investing partners in the Chinese market.
我留意到他每次说话之前总会有停顿
He takes a beat just before he speaks every time.
我怀疑有人在背后操控
I think that someone is giving him directions.
冰冰 你去
Aphrodite, go take a look.
你做我独家代理没问题
I'm okay with you being our exclusive supplier.
但你想入股我的生意
As for investing in our business,
你有这个能力吗
can you really handle that?
只要货源充足价钱合理
As long as the goods keep coming and the price is right,
你们可以当独家
you can be our exclusive supplier.
但入股我们的生意 你们有能力吗
But do you have the muscle to invest in our business?
我们做毒就像银行印现金一样
We drug dealers print cash like banks.
钱不是问题
Money is not a problem.
钱先生 我们做毒的
Mr. Qian, we sell drugs.
钱不是问题
Money is never a problem.
我们跟银行印现金一样
We print cash like banks.
好吧 好吧
Okay,
说说吧 你们打算怎么干
then tell me, how do you want to do it?
告诉他 我们只要南方…
Tell them, I only want the southern region...
音频有钢琴声
I can hear piano in the background.
是在二楼
It's on the second floor!
二楼发现糯卡大儿子拿突
Naw Khar's son Nah Htuu spotted, second floor.
野牛队戒备
Attention, Bulls.
两个目标人物出现
We have two targets in sight.
重点盯住拿突
Make Nah Htuu our top target!
收到
Copy!
目标下来 三个人
Targets are on the way out, three of them!
哪吒 要盯紧这个人
Icarus, we must follow that target!
怎么了
What's going on?
我不是叫你们小心点吗
Didn't I tell you to be extra careful?
我现在马上回来
I'm coming back now.
有人在跟踪你
"Someone is following you"
求救 求救 出事了
(Burmese) Backup! We've got a problem!
哪吒 收到了没有
Icarus, do you copy?
木星 有没有发现目标出来
Area, did you see the target walk out?
现在南方大多数货
Most of the drugs in the south,
都来自金新月
come from the Golden Crescent these days.
他们可以给到比市面低三成的价格
Their price can go 30 percent below the market rate.
帮助我们垄断整个南方
It'll give us a monopoly over the southern region.
那这么说的话
If what you say is true,
我们先做两单试试 好吧
then let's give it a try, shall we?
但我只接受四六分账…
But I only accept a 60-40 split...
我们除了入股
In addition to investing,
还想在中国沿海地区建立分销站
we also want to set up branches along the Chinese coastline.
分销到日本和韩国
We'll move the goods to Japan and Korea,
由你们当代理
and you'll be our agent.
信号在前
The signal's up ahead
两到三百米左右
About two, three hundred meters.
对线 咖啡色那台
The brown car on the opposite lane.
刚才酒店的那个人
The guy at the hotel...
在我们后方
he's right behind us.
他怎么跟来的
How did he find us?
前面路口转左
Turn left at the corner ahead.
是
Got it.
是我 翁煞
It's me, Ongsa.
交易有问题
Something's wrong with the deal!
大家注意
Heads up.
拿突有可能要离开商场
Nah Htuu may be leaving the mall.
是
Hello?
依达 对方是鬼 快撤
Ya Ta, they're cops. Leave now!
高队 钱被发现了
Captain, they found out about the money!
我在叫人过来
I'm sending over backup now.
好
Fine.
你去追他 我掩护你
Go after him! I'll cover you!
蹲下蹲下
Get down! Get down!
二郎
Panoptes!
小冰
Aphrodite!
撤
Go!
大师 你现在在什么位置
Poseidon! Where are you now?
我面对大堂北面出口
I'm at the North Gate!
哥
Xu!
挺住…
Hang in there...
挺住 哥…
Hang in there, Xu...
大师受伤了
Poseidon is down!
我们现在在北门
We're at the North Gate.
赶快派人来增援
We need backup right now!
蹲下蹲下
Get down! Get down!
别动
Don't move!
赶紧拖你哥走
Get your brother out of the way!
哮天 咬
Bingo, go!
别动维安队
Freeze! Police!
维安队来了 高队长走
The local police are here. Go, Captain!
来不及
We're out of time!
别动举高双手
Don't move! Hands up!
高队 对不起
Captain, I'm sorry.
是我大意了
I was careless.
让郭旭他…
And I got Guo Xu...
现在先别说这个
Save that for later.
局长 怎么样了
Chief, how's he doing?
那孩子已经渡过危险期
The child is in stable condition.
可是郭旭的腿保不住了
But Guo Xu's leg can't be saved.
要马上截肢
They have to amputate immediately.
商场这件事闹得这样大
The shopping mall incident was way out of line.
“老板”要你立即离开金三角
Boss wants you to leave the Golden Triangle at once.
“老板”算什么
Who the fuck is he anyway?
他只是这里的菜鸟
He's nothing but a pawn out here.
我才是这里的主
I'm the master here.
要走的是他
He should be the one leaving!
他们动我的人
Those guys made a move on us,
现在要我走
and now he wants me to leave?
你们所有人都忘记我是谁吗
Have you all forgotten who I am?
卡头 冷静
Calm down, boss!
我会尽快找出他的巢穴
I will find out his location as soon as possible.
我们还要先找到他藏金的地方 才好动手
And make sure we locate the gold before we take him out.
当然
Sure.
我没有骗你
I didn't lie to you!
我只知道这么多放过我吧
That's all I know! Let me go!
我说啦求求你 我说啦…
Okay! I will talk! Please stop it!
中国船运毒到金三角
Won't it seem odd for Chinese boats to ship drugs,
会否被人怀疑
into the Golden Triangle?
而且还要杀中国人
And killing Chinese nationals?
我怕事情会搞大
I'm worried this is too big for us.
杀他妈的两三个 有什么问题
What's the big fucking deal with killing a few people?
这又不是第一次有中国人死在湄公河上
It's not the first time Chinese people have died on the Mekong anyway.
把他们全杀掉
Kill them all!
他妈的中国人
Those fucking chinks,
一直想用联合巡逻剿灭我们
they've been looking to use joint patrols to get us.
我就要给他们一个教训
I'll teach them a lesson!
就算全世界对这件事有所怀疑
I don't care if the whole world suspects us.
都拿我们没办法
No one can touch us!
我就是湄公河的主
I am the master of Mekong River!
依达供出来的几个藏匿点都已经清空了
The hiding spots that Ya Ta gave us have all been emptied out.
现在要继续追查下去的方法
The only lead that we have left
只有拿突了
is Nah Htuu.
拿突在维安队手上很容易逃跑
Nah Htuu can easily escape under local police custody.
要趁他还在拘留病房抓他出来
So we must grab him while he's still in the hopsital.
那就干吧
Let's do it.
一会儿如果要动手
If we're really doing this,
我会劫持一个人质
I'll grab a hostage as a diversion.
你先抓他走
Get him out first.
好
Okay.
跟吧
Let's tail them.
拿突少爷和占蓬已经离开医院
Nah Htuu and Jitpong have left the hospital.
在回来路上了
They're on their way back.
这群中国人竟敢挑战我们的能力
(Burmese) If those chinks dare to challenge our power,
我就要给他们看看我们有多强大
we'll show them exactly how powerful we are!
你是我伟大的勇士
You're my great warrior!
别动
Stop!
来来来来这边
Come come come! This way!
我的腿
My leg!
把手给我
Give me your hand!
我的腿
My leg!
好疼放手 放手
It hurts! Slow down!
等等 我去另一边
Wait, I'll go to the other side!
占蓬
Jitpong!
你去哪了
Where have you gone?
占蓬
Jitpong!
救我出来…
Help me out...
Help me out!
救我…
Help me...
闭嘴
Shut up!
把枪给我
Throw me the gun!
我叫你把枪给我
Throw me the damn gun!
方新武 你不可以杀我
Fang, you can't kill me!
就算我死了 你女朋友也活不过来
Killing me won't bring your girlfriend back!
你放过我
Please just let me go!
Let me go!
喂
Hello?
郁平 拿突那边什么情况
Yu Ping, what's the status on Nah Htuu?
叔叔 足球场怎样走
Excuse me, where's the soccer pitch?
你向这边走 转左 再转右
Walk down that way, turn left, then turn right.
然后直行
Then go straight.
你可以重复一遍吗
Could you repeat that?
你向这边走…
Walk down that way...
时间越长证据越少
The more time we take, the more evidence we lose.
这方面我来负责协调
I'll sort that out.
一旦发现糯卡的据点位置
Once we have Naw Khar's position,
立即采取行动
take action right away.
你全权负责指挥
You're in command.
你不能进…
You can't come...
停
Stop!
拦住他他身上有危险品
Stop him! He's carrying something!
停
Stop!
拿…拿突…
Nah Htuu...
拿突跑了…
Nah Htuu got away...
放心郁局
Don't worry, chief.
我们已经捉到拿突了
We've got Nah Htuu.
他供出了糯卡的具是位置
He's already given us Naw Khar's location.
高刚 尽快…尽快行动…
Gao, go get him right away...
哮天 接下来你会很辛苦
It's gonna get tough for you, Bingo.
多吃点
Eat up.
又是你的小情人
Daddy's little lover again?
是
Yeah.
可以看一下吗
Mind if I take a look?
爸爸 小心今天晚上我来找你…
I'll come after you tonight, daddy...
咱俩拍个合影给她发过去吧
Let's take a photo and send it to her.
好
Sure.
我们从拿突口中掌握了糯卡的据点位置
Nah Htuu has given us Naw Khar's location,
但是那里地势复杂
but the terrain of the area is complicated.
而且我们目前
Also,
还不十分清楚对方的武器装备
we can't ascertain what kind of weapons
是在哪一个层面
the enemies are packing.
所以我们要速战速决
So we have to strike hard and fast.
我们会分成四队 从南北两面潜入
We'll split into four teams and penetrate from south and north.
尽快锁定各自目标位置 再同时发起抓捕
Lock down the targets' location ASAP and nab them at once.
这次我们会用实弹作战
We're using live ammos this time,
但是请记住
but remember,
我们的任务是活捉糯卡
our mission is to capture Naw Khar
与及参与这起案件的同谋
and his accomplices alive.
一旦他们被击毙
If they are killed,
等于我们的任务失败
then our mission is a failure.
所以请大家务必保证他们的性命安全
So please do your best to keep them alive.
直升机会一直待命
Helicopters will be standing by.
我们每一队都有一个特频发射器
Each team gets an extra-strength transmitter.
无论是哪一个队得手
Whoever gets the targets,
马上带领目标撤离到集合点
retreat to the meeting point immediately.
用特频发射器通知直升机来接应
Use your transmitter to call the helicopters for extraction.
烤炉已准备好
The stove is ready.
北一到位
North 1 in position.
南二到位
South 2 in position.
北二到位
North 2 in position.
南一到位
South 1 in position.
宋哥
P'Som,
我们不知道他们有多少人
we don't really know how many of them are out there.
不如我们先下手为强
Why don't we strike first?
让他们先打一仗吧
Just let them fight it out.
沙先生最后找到占蓬的尸体
Mr. Zar found Jitpong's body,
但拿突公子还没有找到
but Sai Nah Htuu is still nowhere to be found.
卡头你放心
Rest assured, boss.
我一定会尽快找到拿突公子的
We will find Sai Nah Htuu as soon as possible.
牌真烂呀…
What a terrible hand...
有没有人要换牌
Anyone want to swap?
快下注吧快点
Ante up! Quickly!
高队 一会儿该怎么做
Captain Gao, what should we do?
尽量不要伤害他们
Don't let them get hurt.
北一发现翁煞
Ongsa spotted by North 1.
高队 翁煞交给北二
Captain, North 2 will take Ongsa.
南一报告
This is South 1.
发现目标扎万
We've located Jarwan.
南二报告 发现目标波哈
This is South 2. We've located Boha.
大家继续盯紧目标
Keep a close eye on all targets.
收到
Copy.
还不来早餐
(Burmese) Where's my breakfast?!
糯卡位置确认
Naw Khar's location confirmed.
找死吗
Do you want to die?!
大家准备行动
Get ready for action.
干掉他
Take him out.
出去看看什么事
Go see what's going on!
别动蹲下
Stop! Down! Get down!
别动
Don't move!
待在这
Stay put!
小心 别打中他
Watch out! Don't hit him!
要抓活的
We need him alive!
小心
Be careful.
高队 我在你九点钟方向
Captain, I'm on your nine o'clock.
掩护我我攻上去
Cover me! We're going in!
妈的 中国狗
(Burmese) Fuck you, you chinks!
手雷
Grenade!
有敌人
Enemies approaching!
高队
Captain.
我们有人受伤
We've got injured men here.
你带他们先撤 快
Get them out of here first. Quick!
哪吒
Icarus!
在出口等我
Wait for me at the exit.
是的 卡头
Got it, boss.
小盂 到了没有
Meng, where are you?
到了
I'm here!
走走走
Go go go!
奇夫 直升机马上撒离 你们快过来
Qifu, the helicopters are about to leave, get your asses over here!
北一那边什么情况
What's the status of North 1?
糯卡跑了
Naw Khar escaped.
高队和哮天在追踪他
Captain Gao and Bingo are after him.
就他一个
He's by himself?
是
Yes.
把他的位置传给我
Send me his location.
我是高刚
This is Captain Gao speaking.
糯卡在我们营地后面的山洞里
Naw Khar is inside the cave behind the campsite.
我准备进入
I'm about to go in.
收到回话
Respond if you copy.
糯卡 他在哪
Naw Khar, where is he?
去搜 看看有没有其他暗道
Go see if there's another exit!
宋哥 糯卡在这
P'Som, Naw Khar's right here!
宋哥
P'Som,
可以不杀我吗
can you spare me?!
不能让糯卡落在中国人手里
Don't let Naw Khar get taken by the Chinese!
快点走
Come on, go now!
哮天
Bingo,
现在该你出击了
it's your turn to strike.
成败在此一举
I'm counting on you.
去
Go!
哮天 走
GO, Bingo!
哮天 哮天
Bingo! Bingo!
高队 你收到吗
Captain, do you copy?
高队 我在后面 你准备突围
Captain, I'm right behind you. Get ready to run!
掩护老大 去
Cover the boss, go!
高队 收到吗
Captain, do you copy?
我在河边抓到糯卡
I got Naw Khar by the river.
他伤得很重
He's hurt badly!
我后面有追击
I have attackers on my tail!
坚持住 我马上到
Hang tight! I'm on my way!
高队 我在你七点方向
I'm at your seven o'clock, captain!
如果糯卡死了
If Naw Khar dies,
你最好先给我一枪
you better put a bullet in me.
然后你自己看着办吧
You're on your own after that!
靠近点
Get closer!
再靠近点
高队 我们接近你了
We're almost there, captain!
高队 我在你的十二点方向
Captain, I'm at your twelve o'clock.
准备接应
Prepare for extraction!
掩护方新武
Cover Fang Xinwu!
你们先把糯卡拉上去
Pull Naw Khar up first!
我们再下来救方新武
Then we'll come back down and save Xinwu!
往上拉快
Pull him up! Hurry!
宋哥 我们过来支援你了
We've come to back you up, P'Som!
不能让他走把他打下来
Don't let them leave! Take them down!
高队 不能再等了
Captain! We can't wait any longer!
On November 6, 2012, The Intermediate People's Court of Kunming convicted
Naw Kham, Hsang Kham, Yi Lai, Zha Xiha and Zha Bo
of intentional murder, drug trafficking, kidnapping and hijacking of a vessel.
They were sentenced to death.
方新武在那边的世界待得太久
Fang Xinwu spent too much time in that world.
人是会变的
People change.
其实他当时内心是很矛盾的
He was very conflicted at the time.
那天他杀了刑登以后
After he killed Xing Deng,
我能感受到他的那种痛苦
I could sense that he was in pain.
其实他内心根本没有变
He didn't change one bit.
你可以放心
Take comfort in that.
这次任务完成后 回国吗
When the mission is complete, will you go back to China?
十五年前
15 years ago,
坤沙下网了
Khun Sa was taken out.
却来了一个糯卡
Then Naw Khar took his place.
不知道下一个会是谁
I wonder who the next one will be.